<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CyberKoopas</title>
    <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CyberKoopas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Midnight final] Osint - Esnarcotrafiquants</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-mctf-osint-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-mctf-osint-final/</guid>
      <description>1/5 One of our pilots has been missing for 5 days, our investigation has had no results, but we still have a lead. We know he has a son, and it&amp;#39;s possible that he can tell us more about his father. He&amp;#39;s apparently very active on a social network - his name should be idrisrsbel7. Format : MCTF{} To begin this investigation we have an username : idrisrsbel7 Our first objectives is to find Idris Father&amp;rsquo;s .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday final] Osint - My runaway daughter</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-my-runaway-daughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-my-runaway-daughter/</guid>
      <description>This SOCMINT Osint challenge start with this post that gave us the Facebook profile of the missing daughter. On her profile nothing except her name and a picture. By googling her name we can find her LinkedIn. One of her LinkedIn post we can find her resume link on a Google Drive. Inspecting the element of the web page of the drive, we can find a crucial information to continue our investigation her email : julie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday final] Osint - Where &amp; When</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-wherewhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-wherewhen/</guid>
      <description>**The flag format is : `city_AAAA:MM:dd_HH`** The city is in lowercase and without accent, and the time is approximated to the nearest hour. By using Google Lens we found that this pictures are Nime&amp;rsquo;s arena. Using Google maps we can determine where exactly the picture was taken. Now to find when the picture was taken we check the metadata but of course there were deleted. So we use the sun clearly visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday final] Stegano - strange aeons</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/stegano/en-stegano-stranger-aeson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/stegano/en-stegano-stranger-aeson/</guid>
      <description>On the 2nd of May, the ship XH28U23 saw a strange spacecraft hiding in an asteroid field near the Charybdis A* blackhole. The crew sent us the photo it took but the proximity of the blackhole seems to have done strange things to the asynchronous transmission. They included confidential information in there, the usual way. Can you get back the original image so we can identify the ship ? If it&amp;#39;s a spy-ceship from Ophiuchus, we&amp;#39;ll need to organize an intercept mission as soon as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[PwnMe 2600] Forensic - Silver</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/pwnme/silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/pwnme/silver/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I received a flash drive in my mailbox. It appears that the person who sent me the package was aware that I was using Linux. However, the flash drive self-destructed before I was able to make an image of it. To get the flag, you have to go to the showcase site of the c2 in question. This is real malware, so be careful when running it, use a vm for malware analysis Let&amp;rsquo;s import this image in Autopsy (Forensic Software), it find 3 interesting files : * 1 script .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[PwnMe 2600] Web - Netsapp</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/pwnme/nestapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/pwnme/nestapp/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information The challenge is around a web app challenge based on NestJS. We are given the source code which will make it easier for us to find vulnerabilities to read the flag located in /home/flag.txt.
First Step - The application The functionalities available on the application are :
Create an account Login Once you create an account, you are automatically logged in /infos : We see that the parameter username is reflected on the message given to us once we logged in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Midnight qualif] Crypto - M4g1c</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/m4g1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/m4g1c/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary A file has been encrypted and we have access to the encryption algorithm.
Attached files encrypt.py import sys import os def get_key(length): return os.urandom(length) def encrypt(filename, key): filename_lock = filename + &amp;#34;.lock&amp;#34; data = open(filename, &amp;#34;rb&amp;#34;).read() os.remove(filename) locked = open(filename_lock, &amp;#34;wb&amp;#34;) for idx, i in enumerate(data): locked.write((i ^ key[idx % len(key)]).to_bytes(1, &amp;#34;big&amp;#34;)) if __name__ == &amp;#39;__main__&amp;#39;: if len(sys.argv) != 2: print(f&amp;#34;Usage: {sys.argv[0]} &amp;lt;file to cipher&amp;gt;&amp;#34;) exit(0) else: key = get_key(12) encrypt(sys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Midnight qualif] Osint - Time Traveler</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-osint-qualif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-osint-qualif/</guid>
      <description>1/3 It is said that a time traveler is roaming the social networks right now... his username? &amp;#34;ibm_5100_&amp;#34; Find out more about this person. Let&amp;rsquo;s dig this username using WhatsMyName : It&amp;rsquo;s fit the description about a time traveler. But nothing more&amp;hellip; Since we know it&amp;rsquo;s linked to time travel, let&amp;rsquo;s use WaybackMachine to dig the past of this twitter account : we found one archive with on it the first flag : First Flag : MCTF{t1M€_7r4v3L_O}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Midnight qualif] Pwn - BabyPwn</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/babypwn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/babypwn/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary Exploit the attached binary.
Attached files babypwn (linux binary) libc.so.6 (Associated libc) Solution First, let&amp;rsquo;s check security informations.
checksec babypwn # Arch: amd64-64-little # RELRO: Partial RELRO # Stack: No canary found # NX: NX enabled # PIE: PIE enabled Then, run the program to understand what it does.
./babypwn # There you go, libc leak: 0x7fc01e5f9450 It seems to a classic ret2libc challenge.
We have to test how many chars we need to overwrite RIP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday qualif] Crypto - Trusted 2</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/trusted2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/trusted2/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary Following the leak of an important database in the Sagittarius sector, it has been decided to rework the whole security of the information system. Make sure that the authentication portal is this time secured as it should be.
Attached files server.py #!/usr/bin/env python3 import hashlib from random import randrange from ecdsa import NIST256p, ecdsa G = NIST256p.generator order = G.order() priv = randrange(1, order) pub = G * priv pub = ecdsa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday qualif] Crypto - Trusted</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/trusted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/trusted/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary The situation is bad. The magistrate database from the Sagittarius sector has been leaked! The incident response team continues to see unknown connections in the logs from outside the sector, even though the passwords have all been changed. We suspect the problem is with the authentication portal&amp;hellip; Do something about it!
Attached files server.py #!/usr/bin/env python3 import hashlib from random import randbytes def MAC(msg, key): return hashlib.sha256(key + msg).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday qualif] Osint - A starry night sky</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-a-starry-night-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-a-starry-night-sky/</guid>
      <description>The large library within the Cancer sector contains many documents of all types and from all periods. Among these documents, some have deteriorated over time to the point of finding only snippets of information. This is for example the case of this image where we guess the words 9:00 p.m. and 2022. Try to find the place and the month of shooting. **Flag format: `HACKDAY{COUNTRY_MONTH}`** In English and in capitals !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday qualif] Osint - Vroooom</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-vroooom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-vroooom/</guid>
      <description>The MIA (Intergalactic Automobile Museum) has just received a donation of several photo books from an old (probably very old) car collector. Among the documents was a photo of a car, but the curator was unable to determine its origin... He then decides to call on you, will you be able to give the name of the event where this photo was taken? **The flag is to be constructed in the form: `HACKDAY{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[DaVinciCTF] Crypto - XOR Vigenere</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/dvctf/xor_vigenere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/dvctf/xor_vigenere/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary Context : Leonard forgot to tell you the key he used to encrypt his message.
Would you be able to recover the message he sent you ?
Flag format: dvCTF{REDACTED} found in the message
Attached files message 00011010001111010100110001110000001100000101100100100111011100100101000000100100011101010001000000010111001110100101110001110000001100100101110000100010001101010001100100111001001001110001000000100111001001000111101000000100000100100100101101111011011000100110101101100011000100000110111100001000011000010110000000001111011001010000010100011100000110010000101000001001000010110111110100011010000011010111111100000010011001010000001100001101000101100100010001111110011101000110011100100110001111100101010101110000001100000101111100101101001101110001100101110001 Solution Firstly, we can convert the ASCII message file to a binary file (message.bin). It&amp;rsquo;s possible with CyberChef. Select operation From Binary and download file. Cyberchef parameters :
Delimiter: None Byte Length : 8 We know the flag format is dvCTF{REDACTED}, we can perform a XOR Known plaintext attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[DaVinciCTF] Programming - Principiante</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/dvctf/principiante/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/dvctf/principiante/</guid>
      <description>Challenge information Summary You have to give the correct answer 12 times in a row with a 1s timeout between each answer. Base keyboard is :
_____________________________ | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | |_| |_| | |_| |_| |_| | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | | |___|___|___|___|___|___|___| Examples of expected answers :</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
