<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>GEOINT on CyberKoopas</title>
    <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/tags/geoint/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GEOINT on CyberKoopas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/tags/geoint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Midnight final] Osint - Esnarcotrafiquants</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-mctf-osint-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/midnight/en-mctf-osint-final/</guid>
      <description>1/5 One of our pilots has been missing for 5 days, our investigation has had no results, but we still have a lead. We know he has a son, and it&amp;#39;s possible that he can tell us more about his father. He&amp;#39;s apparently very active on a social network - his name should be idrisrsbel7. Format : MCTF{} To begin this investigation we have an username : idrisrsbel7 Our first objectives is to find Idris Father&amp;rsquo;s .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday final] Osint - Where &amp; When</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-wherewhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-final/osint/en-wherewhen/</guid>
      <description>**The flag format is : `city_AAAA:MM:dd_HH`** The city is in lowercase and without accent, and the time is approximated to the nearest hour. By using Google Lens we found that this pictures are Nime&amp;rsquo;s arena. Using Google maps we can determine where exactly the picture was taken. Now to find when the picture was taken we check the metadata but of course there were deleted. So we use the sun clearly visible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hackday qualif] Osint - Vroooom</title>
      <link>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-vroooom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.cyberkoopas.fr/posts/hackday-qualification/en-vroooom/</guid>
      <description>The MIA (Intergalactic Automobile Museum) has just received a donation of several photo books from an old (probably very old) car collector. Among the documents was a photo of a car, but the curator was unable to determine its origin... He then decides to call on you, will you be able to give the name of the event where this photo was taken? **The flag is to be constructed in the form: `HACKDAY{.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
